# Marshall Asch

💌 masch@uoguelph.ca 🔇 marshallasch.ca 📞 (647) 960-4296 👂 17 Kirkton Road 🛮 in MarshallAsch 🗘 MarshallAsch Toronto, Ontario M3H 1K6

### Summary

I am currently finishing up my Master's of Computer Science with a focus on data storage in mobile ad hoc networks. Over the past several years I have been working on a project to help close the digital divide in northern Canada as well as a couple of open source projects.

## **Employment**

University of Guelph

Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019, Jan. 2020 to Apr. 2020, Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020, Jan. 2021 to Current

Guelph, ON

- Teaching Assistant for the Microcomputers, Operating systems, Cloud computing, Compilers courses.
- Responsible for planning and teaching lab sections.
- · Graded and provided feedback on student assignments, midterms, and exams.
- · Assisting students in office hours, discussion boards, and emails for both online and in person offerings.

Left May 2019 to Aug. 2020

Iniversity of Guelph Mitacs Intern

Maple Ridge, BC

· Conducting research on Mesh Networks and data storage as part of an industry partnership for my masters degree with a team of Master students, a PhD candidate, as well as developers working in the industry.

University of Guelph Jan. 2019 to Apr. 2019

Guelph, On

- · Led development, integration, and testing of the web API for the eNuk environmental and health monitoring application.
- · Led weekly meetings to coordinate software development.
- Collaborated with external development team who was consuming our API.
- · Responsible for maintaining and administrating servers and 3rd party resources for the project.

Left May 2018 to Aug. 2018

RightMesh App Developer

- Developed Android applications as a part of a small team using the RightMesh mesh networking
- Provided weekly progress updates to the project stake holders.

#### Lakeridge Health

Oshawa, ON

- Designed and built internal web tools for auditing and incident reporting.
- · Assisted with the configuration and deployment of an out of band network to monitor the network around the hospital.
- Performed the migration of Windows SCCM and SQL servers in an enterprise environment.
- Provided IT support in an enterprise environment to non technical users.

#### Volunteering

Ontario University Fair Nov. 2019 to Nov. 2019 Toronto, On

· Represented the university at the Ontario university show case to prospective high school students.

Society of Computing and Information Science System Administrator

Sept. 2018 to Apr. 2020

Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

July 2017 to Aug. 2017

Guelph, ON

- In charge of redesigning and rebuilding the website and managing a team of other students.
- · Responsible for maintaining the servers, web services, and maker space.

University of Gueloh Climbing Club Climbing Gym Monitor Guelph. On

· Responsible for setting routes, teaching basic principles and ensuring participant safety.

University of Guelph ·

University of Guelph ·

College of Engineering and Physical Sciences Society

contributions to the university community.

Nov. Dr. James Linders Scholarship 2018 A scholarship for having the highest average in the core 3rd year Computer Science courses, in the Computer

#### Education

University of Guelph May 2019 to Current Masters Computer Science 2021

University of Guelph Sept. 2015 to Apr. 2019 Bachelor of Computing, Honours 2019 Maintained Dean's Honours List every semester Received the University of Guelph Entrance Scholarship for obtaining a minimum average of 85% at a registered Ontario Secondary School.

#### Projects

Oct. 2020 to Current liquidctl Active maintainer for the cross-platform CLI and Python drivers for AIO liquid coolers and other devices.

May 2018 to Jan. 2020

A community lead eco-health monitoring application for an Inuit community in Rigolet, Labrador using RightMesh as a method to try to help bridge the gap in the digital divide where there is very little infrastructure in place for digital communication in the community.

botomir Dec. 2020 to Current Discord server bot written in node.js that I am currently actively working on in my spare time.

#### Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Node.js, BASH, Java, git, Javascript, C, HTML, PHP, sql, python

#### **Awards**

University of Guelph ·	Apr.
Canada Graduate Scholarships-Master's Program	2020
(\$17500) Natural Sciences and Engineering Resea	rch
Council of Canada (NSERC) Scholarship	

University of Guelph · Apr. CEPS Dean's Tri-Council Scholarship 2020 (\$5000) Deans Scholarship awarded to NSERC award holders

University of Guelph · Feb. Ontario Graduate Scholarship 2020

(\$5000) A merit based academic scholarship.

Erin Angus Graduate Student Award Awarded to a graduate student for making significant

contributions to student life.

Demonstrated academic excellence and outstanding

University of Guelph ·

Science Major.